aut.ac.nz 2009-12-28

# Web Privacy and Security Statement - AUT University

Thank you for visiting our website. AUT has made a commitment to protecting the privacy of users of our website as we appreciate that site visitors and users are concerned about their privacy and the security of any information that they may provide.

Any personal information provided by site visitors will be made available only to authorised staff of the University.

AUT undertakes to collect and maintain any personal information in a manner consistent with the principles outlined in the Privacy Act 1993.

Like most websites, we monitor usage to help us to make it useful to as many visitors as possible and to map web trends. To do this we collect some information about users of the site, and we may also ask you for information in order to provide a service to you. Details of what we collect and how it is used are contained in this statement.

 **Use of cookies and other information collection technologies**

Internet cookies are small strings of text placed on users’ hard drives during the data exchange that happens when a browser points to a website. Cookies allow a website to store information on a user’s machine and retrieve it later. Cookies and other information collection technologies can only store information that is explicitly provided by the user or visitor in the first place, or information the website already knows about the user, such as their IP address.

Our AUT website uses cookies for identifying unique visitors and proving your identity should you attempt to access a restricted part of the site. For example, the pass-worded staff or students.

Most browsers can be set to accept or reject cookies. You can choose to adjust your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when they are being used. You should be aware however that sometimes, rejecting cookies results in a loss of some website functionality.

 **Site usage**

When you visit our website, we make a record of your visit using tools such as GOOGLE Analytics and report software from our web servers.   
We log information, which is used for statistical purposes of site performance. For example:  

  * the IP address of the computer you are using or an IP that is dynamically allocated by your internet service provider;
  * the date and time of your visit;
  * the pages accessed and documents downloaded;
  * the file size of the pages downloaded;
  * the type of browser used and screen resolution;
  * the referring page (ie last page visited before entering AUT’s site).  

 **Email and feedback information**

All email correspondence sent to this site is treated as a public record and may be retained by us for future consideration.

Email messages may be monitored by our Web and Technology Services support staff for system trouble shooting and maintenance purposes and some emails received by our website support staff may be forwarded to other AUT staff for appropriate action if required. Staff of AUT will not disclose these details to third parties without your consent (unless required by law).

For full details of our Internet, Intranet and E-Mail Policy please [click here](http://www.aut.ac.nz/staff/policies/pd_policy.php?policyid=100257&sectionid=12)

 **Specific AUT Policies Related to Privacy**

Personal Information  
This policy sets out the criteria and procedures to ensure the safeguarding of personal information held by the University and provides clear guidelines for the collection, maintenance of and access to personal information, and procedures for action if such information is misused. [More](http://www.aut.ac.nz/staff/policies/pd_policy.php?policyid=100249)

Information Security Policy  
AUT’s Information Security Policy provides the essential framework in which information may be shared whilst ensuring that the necessary safeguards are in place. [More ](http://www.aut.ac.nz/staff/policies/pd_policy.php?policyid=100258)
